<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Like the waves roll with the moon]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bryant's personal blogging space for everything work and life.]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 11:38:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Hello 2020]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello! Whelp, towards the end of 2019 there were so many things happening at the same time, that I totally neglected the blog. This semester…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/hello-2020/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/hello-2020/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello! Whelp, towards the end of 2019 there were so many things happening at the same time, that I totally neglected the blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This semester I will be taking up two modules which are Neural Networks &amp;#x26; Deep Learning and Information Visualization. Information Visualization might seem like an odd choice, but I do think it can be a really beneficial module to take! As a software engineer, I noticed that from a technical standpoint, it is often easy to forget about the significance of the meaning behind the data. Hopefully opportunities will arise for me to practice story telling with the help of visualizations that we build in the course of the semester! Looking forward to practicing some vis-skills with D3 and Tableau too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I happened to also start my rotation to a new team in November. We started on a project partnering with Engineers from Microsoft to build search application on Microsoft Azure. So far, the whole experience has been more than ideal! It has been such a fulfilling journey over the past few sprints. It has been a pleasure coding along side likeminded experts! Upon reflection, I realise now that its not only the technical accomplishments that give me the sense of satisfaction from my job, it is mainly the chance to collaborate with amazing people that makes this job fun. Communication really is key huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this rate, I’m really looking forward to what’s coming up in 2020. I’ll provide more updates soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Being yourself]]></title><description><![CDATA[I just want to say one thing today, it’s a really random thought: People can have conceptions of who you are. At times, we don’t know who we…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/being-yourself/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/being-yourself/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I just want to say one thing today, it’s a really random thought:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People can have conceptions of who you are. At times, we don’t know who we really are either. Does the concept of oneself exist?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Time Management]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m going to penning down my thoughts today on time management! The past 3 weeks have really been hectic, juggling work, school and my…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/time-management/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/time-management/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to penning down my thoughts today on time management!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past 3 weeks have really been hectic, juggling work, school and my volunteering duties. At work, I was spending most of my time preparing for my move to a new team. On a daily basis, I was implementing and testing last minute requirements that were given to me, 3 weeks before my move. And I was also documenting and explaining to my stakeholders on how the application I built works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With school work, I have been working on multiple assignments on and off, and often prioritising those that are nearing their deadlines first. There is definitely still plenty of room for improvement, as I have been neglecting some of these projects. ( I’m frantically catching up on those that I have neglected ) I have been pondering on I could be utilizing my time better, especially since I’m spending at least 8 hours of my day in the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I toyed around with a two strategies, mainly waking up early and working on school related stuff before going to work, and reading materials on the way to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waking up earlier does feel great. It gives me that extra one to two hours to catch up on something, or to do some sort of revision. I usually find it hard to get into the zone to deep dive into an assignment in the morning! But it does seems to be the perfect time to be watching a webcast for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading school materials on commute is usually a challenge. On the train to work, I usually get distracted quite easily by my surrounding environment. It gets worse when I try to read on the bus, on the way to NUS. (Weak me tends to get motion sickness lol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having much lesser time, during this period of time did get me thinking about my priorities ( In somewhat a particular order ):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spending time with my loved ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work, and getting things done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;School work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparing for Code in the Community sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past 2 months or so, some of the things that I had to forgo were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spending time with friends. ( My weekly Mahjong nights for example :P )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading. I really miss reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really looking forward to reading again once exam ends!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technically I should be able to find time to read, but it does not feel good reading when I know there are materials I should be reading..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hobby stuff like watercolor and Netflixing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup, in summary I think there is still room for improvement in terms of time management, and I really never thought this would be easy! Optimistically thinking, these busy periods come in bursts of 2-3 months every semester which happens twice a year. Its really a hectic period, but I believe this experience will allow me cultivate the important skill of time management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to go back to doing assignments lah.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Clogged Ears]]></title><description><![CDATA[“How to listen in a noisy world”, heh that’s like some ultimate click bait material. Anyway, my ears really felt clogged up recently. It…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/clogged-ears/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/clogged-ears/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;“How to listen in a noisy world”, heh that’s like some ultimate click bait material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my ears really felt clogged up recently. It literally felt that way! I could not even hear what my boss was saying at times, but I think i managed somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what helped, but I immediately went for a swim upon reaching home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know that feeling when you breathe, and you hear the air moving along with something in your ears? Yup, sounds gross and it absolutely is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I’m not sounding like my usual self in this post, and it might be the excess caffeine kicking in. And maybe I’m starting to go abit cray.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Firsts]]></title><description><![CDATA[This blog post is going to be a brief recount of recent experiences and events! Some time back, a friend and colleague of mine at work…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/first-lesson-as-teacher/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/first-lesson-as-teacher/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This blog post is going to be a brief recount of recent experiences and events!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time back, a friend and colleague of mine at work reached out to me for assistance. He was tasked to organise a 10 week volunteering session in collaboration with Code in the Community (CITC), and was looking for someone keen on being the instructor. Teaching a class of kids did seem intimidating to me, but I agreed to help out anyway. Boy, it has been one of the best decision I have made in the recent past. I cannot say for sure that everything will go as expected or smoothly (as usual), but I believe that the experiences over the next 2 months will justify my decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before my first session as an instructor, I received a suggestion to “sit in” on one of the weekend lessons conducted in conjunction with CITC. Hence, I have been helping out with CITC sessions at a nearby public library the last couple of weeks. Lessons are two hours, and kids aged between 7 and 12 are exposed to computational thinking through the Scratch programming platform. The instructor leading the class is really experienced, and I do have alot to learn from him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His success in keeping the kids engaged is probably due to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being ready for class. This by no means simply mean understanding the content! It involves looking through every detail of the content, and masterfully pinpointing potential pitfalls. Are some of the concepts or words in the slides that are ambiguous?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being experienced with class management. Teaching someone one-to-one is significantly different from teaching a class of kids. It is important to continuously notice group dynamics and make changes if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being able to strike a balance between being fun and being stern. Kids love to have fun. But things can quickly get out of hand in class and get rowdy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being good looking. (Just kidding! HAHA) I think its important to maintain your composure even when unexpected things happen, and defintely ALWAYS SMILE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the above points in mind, I prepared for my lesson for last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a blast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class was rowdy. In fact, I think it could potentially be the most rowdy CITC class in history. I could tell all the volunteers were taken aback initially. The initially thirty minutes was tough. Account creation was a boring task, and it was hard to keep the students engaged in what was happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, things gradually took a turn for the better once lessons began! Though I was also learning on the job, picking up small tricks and tips from others really helped here. Based on my observation, roughly 90% of the students were genuinely interested, and were engaged in building up their own projects on scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://scratch.mit.edu/projects/327301941/&quot;&gt;this project&lt;/a&gt; done by one of my students! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now I’m really looking forward to future lessons, despite how challenging they might be.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World is Overrated]]></title><description><![CDATA[It been awhile since I last blogged! 2019 so far has been full of surprises, with more downs than ups so far. Nonetheless, like how the…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It been awhile since I last blogged! 2019 so far has been full of surprises, with more downs than ups so far. Nonetheless, like how the waves continue to roll with the moon, we shall persist!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School officially starts tomorrow. I will be attempting to juggle work from my full time job as a software engineer and as a MComp student in NUS. With the new blog, I intend to document my upcoming experiences in NUS and work. Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>